We can access elements in a DataFrame in different ways.
我们有多种办法可以访问 DataFrame 里的元素
In general, we can access rows, columns,
总地来说 我们可以用行标签和列标签
or individual elements by using the row and column labels.
来访问行、列和个别元素
Let's see some examples.
来看些例子
Here's a DataFrame we created in the last video.
这是我们在上一个视频里创建的 DataFrame
We can access the bikes column using the column label,
像这样用列标签 我们就可以访问 bikes 一列了
like this, and use a list of the column labels to access multiple columns.
而输入一个列标签列表 我们就可以访问多个列了
We can access a row using the row index label,
我们可以用行索引标签来访问某一行
and the value at a specific row and column like this.
也可以像这样访问某一行、某一列的某个值
It's important to know that when accessing individual elements in a DataFrame,
注意 在访问 DataFrame 的某个元素时
like in this last example,
比如上一个例子
the column label always comes first,
你应该先写列标签
and then the row label.
然后才是行标签
If you provide the row label first, you'll get an error.
如果你先写了行标签 代码就会出错
We can also modify our DataFrames by adding rows or columns.
我们也可以修改 DataFrame 为其添加行和列
Suppose we decided to add a shirts column to our DataFrame, to do this,
假设我们想给 DataFrame 添加一个名为 shirts 的列
we can define our shirts column containing
为此我们可以先像这样
the quantity for each of the two store rows like this.
为该列定义两个商店的存货量
This added a new column to the end of our DataFrame.
这样 DataFrame 末端就会添加一个新列了
We can also add new columns using
要添加新列
arithmetic operations on other columns of our DataFrame.
我们也可以对 DataFrame 的其它列进行算术运算
For example, we can create a new column called
比如 我们可以创建一个叫 suits (套装) 的新列
suits by computing the sum of the shirts and pants column.
只需计算列 shirts 和 pants 的总和即可
Suppose now, that you opened
假设现在你开了一家新店
a new store and you want to add that as a row on your DataFrame.
想在 DataFrame 中加一行
To add rows to our DataFrame,
要给 DataFrame 添加行
we first have to create a new DataFrame with those rows,
首先要为该行新建一个 DataFrame
and then append it to the original DataFrame.
再将其追加给原 DataFrame
Let's see how this works.
我们来看具体操作
Here is a dictionary of the items in
这个字典记录了新商店的物品
our new store that we will use to create a DataFrame.
我们会用该字典来创建 DataFrame
We can now add this row to our store items DataFrame using the append method.
现在我们可以用方法 append 将这一行追加给 DataFrame store_items 了
After appending to the DataFrame,
追加后
the columns have been placed in alphabetical order.
各列会按字母顺序排列
We can also add new columns to our DataFrame by
我们也可以选择 DataFrame 里原有的数据
selecting data that already exists in our DataFrame.
从而给 DataFrame 添加新列
For example, let's say you want to stock stores two and three with new watches.
假设你要给 stores 2 和 3 添加新的手表库存
So you decide to add a new column called new watches to your DataFrame,
所以你要给 DataFrame 添加一个名为 new watches 的列
and say you want the quantity of
假设你希望新的手表库存
these new watches to be the same as the watches already in stock.
和已有的手表库存一样多
Since we only want the stock stores two and three,
由于我们只想增加 stores 2 和 3 的库存
we can index them like this.
所以我们可以像这样使用索引
It is also possible to insert new columns into the DataFrame anywhere we want.
我们也可以把新列插入 DataFrame 的任意位置
The insert method allows us to specify the location,
方法 insert 需要指定插入位置
label, and data of the column we want to add.
标签以及我们想添加的列的数据
Let's use this to add a new column called shoes right before the suits column.
我们来用这个方法在 suits 列之前增加一行名为 shoes 的列
The first argument is loc or location, we put five.
第一个参数为 loc 也就是位置 我们设为 5
So, 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
0、1、2、3、4、5
So, we actually inserted the shoes column before the watches column.
因此我们会在 watches 列前插入 shoes 列
The second argument is the label,
第二个参数是标签
and the last is the data.
最后一个是数据
In addition to adding rows and columns,
除了添加行和列外
we can also delete them.
我们还可以删除行和列
We can use the pop and drop methods to do this.
为此 我们可以用方法 pop 和 drop
The pop method allows us to delete columns while
方法 pop 可以删除列
the drop method can be used to delete both rows and columns by using the axis keyword.
而使用关键字 axis 方法 drop 不仅可以删除列 还可以删除行
Let's see some examples.
来看些例子
We can delete the new watches column using pop which is used to remove columns.
我们可以用专门删除列的方法 pop 来删除 new_watches 列
Now, we will move the watches and shoes columns with drop,
现在 我们用 drop 来删除 watches 和 shoes 列
which can be used to remove columns if we set axis to one.
使用该方法删除列时 只需将关键字 axis 设为 1 即可
We'll use that same method to remove
还是用这个方法
the rows store two and store one by setting axis to zero.
把 axis 设为 0 我们就可以删除 store 2 和 store 1  这两行了
Sometimes, we might need to change the row and column labels.
有时候我们需要修改行标签和列标签
Let's change the bikes column label to hats using the rename method.
我们来用方法 rename 把 bikes 列的标签改为 hats
This takes in a dictionary with original label as keys and the new labels as values.
该方法接受一个字典 字典以原标签为键 以新标签为值
We can see the bikes has been renamed to hats.
可以看到 bikes 已经改成 hats 了
Now, let's change the row label using the rename method.
现在 用方法 rename 来更改行标签
We can change the index label of store three to last store like this.
我们可以像这样把索引标签 store 3 改为 last store
Notice here, we set the index parameter to the dictionary.
注意 这里是把参数 index (索引) 设为了字典
Whereas in the previous cell,
而在上一个代码单元格中
we set columns to the dictionary.
我们是把 columns (列) 设为字典的
We can also set the index to be one of the existing columns in the DataFrame, like this.
我们也可以将索引设为 DataFrame 的任一列 像这样
Now, we're using the values in the pants column as our row index labels.
现在我们就是用 pants 列里的值作为行索引标签了